Miss around our introductions,
and you were the last one.
Okay, my name is Sharon Murray.
I'm the payroll manager here at XLHR.
The.
Wonderful. Very nice to meet you.
So the plan today, Bill and team,
is to walk through the platform.
We'll show you both our client-facing
side of our platform,
as well as the administrative side of the
platform that would be facing you guys.
And there's no way you can possibly throw
Shane off as he's
walking through the platform.
So if you have any questions that pop out,
please feel free to jump in.
And I'll, without further further ado,
just turn it over to Shane here.
Hey, thanks, Antaeus.
Let me share my screen.
And for even from what Bill saw at Prism
Live, things have been updated,
improved upon.
The feedback we've received from our
service providers has been very valuable
so that we're, you know,
introducing this and providing the right
tools that you might need.
to service your clients.
So this is what Prism Global is.
It resides within Prism as a module.
So you go into Prism,
click on the single sign-on,
it takes you directly into the Prism
Global module.
So as our service providers have all
their US employees in Prism,
this would be all their international
employees outside the US.
on Prism Global.
And this platform manages pay for kind of
three types of classifications.
Contractors, independent contractors,
people you're paying in other countries
on a project basis or an interim basis.
EOR, we're worthy employer of record,
full-time regular employees that are
living in another country.
And then also when you have clients that
might have a entity established where
they have a branch, a subsidiary,
some legal structure in a foreign country
and are paying employees directly,
which we just consider payroll,
we're going to run the payroll for those
employees or that client in that country.
And so the main key question is,
do they have an entity or do they not?
If they don't,
we use our employer of record. If they do,
we're running the payroll for them in
that country.
The nice thing is it's all in one
platform.
So whether your client has contractors,
EOR, direct payroll, it doesn't matter.
We can all see them in one platform.
And this is what you would see as a
service provider when you first log into
Of the system is kind of an overall view
of all your clients and their headcount,
so it does distinguish between
contractors, direct payroll employees,
and employer of record,
so you can quickly see that from a kind
of overall headcount perspective.
You can see here my different clients
that I have and all the...
workers that they might have,
the growth that they're seeing,
and then kind of where that distribution
is by countrywide, right?
So you're seeing all your clients and
their international employees kind of in
one spot. I can, of course,
toggle between EOR, direct payroll,
or contractors and kind of see where
things are at in the world.
As I go through this,
I'll go through this briefly,
then I'll jump right into the client side,
which is where most of the magic happens.
Here's just my client list where I can go
in there and see all my different clients.
And then a general overall worker view of
all the different types. So of course,
I can look at just different types of
engagement.
If it's just my direct payroll employees,
I can see them here.
If I want to include EOR or others,
I can always toggle to see what that
employee looks like.
I'm seeing them also in terms of going
through the onboarding and those that are
active.
So I can see that general view of like,
I've got a few that are still onboarding,
where are they at in that process versus
those that are active.
And up and going, OK.
The invoices here is the invoice section.
There's two different types of invoices
depending on how you want to get set up
with Prism.
We have a reseller model where we would
invoice you for the services and so forth.
You would then turn around and invoice
your client.
We also have a referral model where we
have a direct relationship with the end
client.
And so we invoice them directly and then
refer back to a referral commission,
if you will.
So those are different types there.
In this scenario right here,
this would be the service provider
invoice. Again,
the invoice that we're sending from PRISM
to you in terms of what the services are
provided. You can see what those are.
Again, there's contractor invoices.
Direct payroll and EOR,
and so I could click on that.
I can view the invoice and this is going
to show simply the fees for our payroll
service in that country. Okay.
And then the client invoice here is where
you can have an invoice that would be
from you to your client with the
recommended rates and so forth that
you're really selling this for. And again,
you can see that here.
Whether you're using our system or just
rolling that up to your own system,
you have all the back office
documentation for what those invoices
look like right here.
And then from an admin perspective,
these are just the different admins that
I have in my system so that you can
provide access to them.
They can see different clients,
you can segregate that so they only have
permission to see certain clients,
or they can have a global overall view,
et cetera.
In the settings section is where the bank
account information is going to go and
then your client pricing.
So what you are going to be charging the
client if you're in a reseller
environment, right?
We're going to be providing the invoice
and selling to you at a wholesale price.
You in turn then resell that at a resale
price to your client.
And this is where you can set up all
those different rates.
and so forth here.
From a payroll perspective,
there's set up fees, ongoing fees,
monthly fees, et cetera.
I can provide price overrides.
So if there's a particular country,
and this happens very often in global
payroll,
some countries are just really more
complicated.
Brazil is always going to be complicated.
So it usually is more expensive to do
payroll, employer of record,
and so forth in Brazil and other
countries.
So there's some overrides that we can
adjust the pay.
Those invoice amounts accordingly, OK?
So that's kind of what you're seeing from
an overall service provider view,
is this service provider dashboard and
all the settings that you can have there.
Okay.
Any questions on this before I dive right
into the client view?
This is kind of more of an overview of
kind of what you would experience as a
service provider.
Can I just ask a question? This is Helen.
I'm in sales.
Yeah.
Probably a really dumb question because I
don't do payroll,
but what is the difference between direct
payroll and EOR, the employee of record?
Great question.
It really determines on if your client
has a legal entity established in that
foreign country. Okay.
Legal, legal entity. OK.
Yeah,
and that entity could be a branch office,
Right.
a subsidiary, an LLC, something.
If they do not,
and they want to hire someone in that
country, they must use an EOR.
ER understood. Got it. Thank you.
Yeah. Now,
you will run across clients that are
doing that where they're paying someone
directly.
They don't have an entity in that country.
You can do that, but it's not compliant.
And it can,
there's a really high risk and liability
associated with that,
which is why employer of record
eliminates all that liability.
Well, I have a,
what if I have an existing client in the
Right.
States and they now want to open a branch
or put employees in Mexico?
Mmh.
Yeah, if...
No, no office in Mexico, just employees.
Are they looking to establish an entity
in Mexico?
No.
then they could use employer of record in
Mexico. Absolutely. Yep. Yep.
Okay, got it. Understood.
Mexico actually has some pretty strict
rules as it relates to employment in
Mexico, having an entity or not.
They do not mess around.
M.
So they for sure do not want to just be
wiring money to people in Mexico.
But again,
That entity piece is important,
and it happens all the time.
We want to hire these people,
but we don't want to expand our business
into that country.
So how do we legally employ them?
And that's where employer of record
happens in Mexico. Absolutely.
But would you would you recommend that
they establish an entity?
The.
In in your experience,
as opposed to to do as opposed to to the
employer of record,
if they establish an entity,
what's the advantage?
It's more of a business decision.
From a strictly an employment perspective,
Okay.
I would not recommend it because
establishing an entity now,
Okay.
Mhm.
I have a legal presence in Mexico.
I need to have a registered office.
I need to have legal representation.
I've got to report taxes.
All these other things come in.
So I always look at it as a business
Understood. Understood. Got it.
Mmh.
decision.
What's your business looking to do in
Mexico? If it's just access talent,
Mmh.
EOR all day long. If it's, no,
I want to put a branch office,
Understood.
I want to be a sell directly,
those other things come into play,
No.
then you would want to have an entity.
So go ahead, Antaeus.
You were going to mention something or
some, or maybe it was someone else.
Yeah, and...
No, no, no, you covered it all.
It's formal complex, especially...
Shane just nailed it.
I don't want to beat a dead horse there.
It was a great question, though. Great,
great question.
Okay, understood.
Yeah, and I was going to say, Helen, like,
given our experience in the past with a
certain big client of yours that we used
to service that was in all kinds of
Right.
places,
there was the talk of getting the legal
entity put in place for them,
but even getting an application filled
out was complicated and cumbersome for
them. So
We essentially did the outsource PEO
route, right?
Right, okay. Well, it has no advantage.
It sounds like there's no advantage to
establishing the entity, just problems.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah. Again,
it's more of a business decision overall.
I mean,
now I've planted my flag in Mexico, right?
And it's a big, that's a big deal.
If it's just to hire people,
it's usually not the right way to go.
So yeah,
and we could talk about some of those
reasons why, but yeah, in general,
that's the big decision they need to make.
Do I want to establish an entity there?
It's also really expensive.
So if only talking about a handful of
employees,
the costs associated far outweigh the
benefits of that entity versus we've
already done the legwork,
just hire them through us. So.
Are there countries where you have to
establish an entity because the EOR
Ring.
doesn't work? Or can you do EOR anywhere?
I don't know of any.
EOR is available everywhere.
Okay.
The Isle of Man,
if you ever just try to go to the Isle of
Man, you cannot do EOR there because they,
but you also can't set up a foreign
entity.
And a citizen of the Isle of Man has to
set up the entity themselves.
I don't think you're going to the Isle of
All right, well.
Man.
But that's the only one I can think of.
Yeah, Helen, that's on the list.
That's on the blacklist,
then we can't go there.
Yeah, yeah. There are some countries,
and this is very common,
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
it's even a practice of ours.
If you have an entity in that country,
you may not use EOR.
You would have to hire them directly.
Gotcha.
So that's something that also comes into
play. Canada, Mexico especially,
if I have a legal entity,
I cannot use an employer of record.
One of the main reasons why is there is a
law that they established,
I want to say five or six years ago.
It's a profit sharing,
basically payment to all your employees.
If I have a Mexican business,
the end of the year,
I have certain profits.
The government calculates through a
formula,
the profit sharing I send to the
employees.
And you have to share, yeah,
you have to share, yes.
what companies were doing was like, oh,
they're not my employees that are through
an employer of record.
So I don't have to share those profits.
And the Mexican government said,
that's not how it works.
So they stopped that and said,
if you have an entity in Mexico,
you may not use an employer of record.
So anyway, so yeah, lots of reasons why,
but most of the time,
if you have an entity,
you cannot use an employer of record.
Sun.
Okay,
so let me jump right into what your
client would be seeing directly with
interfacing with theirs.
And the nice thing about the platform is
that you can go into and impersonate and
basically dive into their instance, right?
If you're a reseller,
I can look inside my client's Prism
platform.
which is located here,
and either provide any support or answer
questions.
But this is where they now would see
their global employees, right?
This dashboard gives us a quick
indication on what we need to do,
and it depends on the type of employee,
right?
If I have employer of record employees,
I could go into here.
and make sure that the pay period looks
correct. Now,
I've got a lot of different countries
associated in here,
but if I quickly open up Ava's,
I can see all her wages, taxes, benefits.
I can expand this to see everything to
make sure everything looks correct.
Down here below, this is a great feature.
It shows quickly what the employee
gross to net looks like.
You see there's quite a bit of taxes here
and what the total employer costs are
going to be.
And that's something that as you get
involved in global payroll and EOR is
that the social charges,
the payroll taxes in other countries are
very different and can be very expensive.
So just having an understanding of what
that looks like here.
And it actually gives you a quick
currency conversion from Canadian to US
dollars.
So you just kind of see quickly what that
looks like.
So this would be an EOR type of pay
period.
If I go back to the dashboard and they
have a direct entity and they're paying
them directly. Again, similarly,
here's the one for Mexico.
I would show them in Mexican pesos.
their wages, taxes, everything here,
broken down and then converted quickly
into US dollars. Also the employer costs.
There's quite a bit of employer costs
associated with Mexico,
so they can quickly see what that looks
like. Okay.
So, this is where that would, yeah.
Is there a way to drill down into those
costs?
Like I see, like, uh,
tax and contributions, like, is, ohh,
Yeah, you can drill into that.
So you can see what the specific
right there, okay.
insurance, payroll tax, et cetera.
Each country,
they have a list of all the required
taxes. You can drill into that.
Absolutely. Yep.
And is there an option to not show the
detail either or or like other than that,
like like to bundle an invoice versus?
Um...
Ors.
What should worry there, Bill?
We just have clients on the PEO side
domestically where we bundle the invoice
and there's like a service fee and that
might include like taxes as well.
So everything's just one number basically.
Like if we say we're charging them a
Oh, okay.
percentage of payroll, of gross payroll,
right?
gross wages, we wouldn't show the detail.
But I don't know if it really matters so
much. I just wondered,
because we were looking at the detail.
Yeah, and um,
have you decided or did on Tancy discuss
whether they wanted to be a reseller or a
referral arrangement yet?
We didn't get that that deep,
I don't believe. Yeah, yeah.
Okay, that's fine.
Yeah, I mean, honestly, we would be,
I mean, we could, we would be a reseller,
Reseller would be a reseller, yeah.
absolutely.
Okay. So in that, yeah, in that respect,
absolutely,
That's why Helen's on the phone.
you would not need to share all the
details with your client.
You could just simply roll that number up
and say, well,
here's the total amount here.
And that gets, you know,
there's your payroll or overall taxes or
however you want to do that through your
payroll system.
So yeah,
so you don't necessarily need to show all
the details if you don't want to.
Yeah,
I don't know how it would go into our
But what we're going to provide to you is
this level.
system. No, I get it. Okay.
And then I guess just from a quick thing
on the billing perspective, like,
is everything like a per check type of
fee that you charge us that we would
charge or there's no like license fee or
anything. It's just a...
based on employees and number of checks
being run.
Yeah,
so are we talking about employer of
record, that service specifically? Yeah.
There's just a monthly fee. Yeah,
Yeah, yeah, I think generally, yeah.
there's just one monthly fee.
They're in the invoice that you see.
And let me go back to that.
Does that fee is that fee affected by the
number of employees or just the monthly
In fact, I will go to the end.
fee?
there's a per employee per month fee.
And if I go to the EOR,
this is just an example.
If I go to this invoice here,
then you will see that it's pretty simple,
our invoices. There's the wages,
the actual payment to the employee,
the social charges and taxes in that
country, and then our fee.
So it's a really pretty
basic,
it's a per employee per month fee for the
EOR services. Yeah.
There's some setup fees and deposit and
Okay.
some other things that Antaeus will
outline, but on a monthly basis,
it's just payroll, taxes, and our fees.
Question,
is it a setup fee just for us or is it a
setup fee for each of the people that we
use as a reseller?
It would be a it would be a setup fee per
employee that it gets onboarded onto the
EOR.
Okay.
So each time your client onboards a new
employee in Mexico,
there's a setup fee for that employee.
Okay,
what happens if I have a second client?
Yeah.
Is there another setup fee or is it just
one setup fee to us?
Yes.
Nope, it's a per employee setup fee.
So even another client, yep,
per client.
it's always dependent on the employee.
So all the fees are **** around that
Matt per client.
employee. So there's a setup fee,
a deposit, another fees for that setup,
and then there's a monthly fee just for
that employee.
And that's always associated with that.
Is this like, is this number here,
like $599 per month, like,
is that typical? That's pretty high.
That's a good average.
That's kind of an average for the end
client,
what they would pay from an employer of
Right, that's the client, yeah.
record. Yeah. Yeah.
You as a reseller would have a wholesale
Yeah, I know it definitely.
rate. So.
Okay, okay, good. But I, I mean,
what kind of number are we talking about?
But that is what...
The wholesale rate, like...
80% of that or just generally. I mean,
you know, I'm not holding you to anything.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's...
I'm just kind of wondering.
I think it's 40% is about what the rate
is lower than that.
So it's right in there in the contract.
So we have the table built out.
Okay.
There's 3 different tiers of countries
that, like I said,
there's some countries that are more or
less expensive or more complicated,
Yeah.
but it's about a 40% right. Now,
that's our suggested retail price.
Okay.
But if you want to lower or raise that
based on what you're selling it for,
that's up to you.
But we kind of give you guidance what's
Gotcha.
pretty much market average for those
countries.
Yeah,
and I know I've been shopping some of
this stuff in the past, outsourcing it,
like it's pretty expensive in a lot of
Yeah.
countries, but way more than the US,
honestly.
Yeah, yeah, it can be.
Absolutely.
That's sometimes the biggest hurdle in
Yeah.
discussing EOR,
especially if they've only dealt with the
US.
They're used to single digit or very low
headcount PEPMs.
But when they're going to another country,
it is a lot more because like we
discussed earlier, we've done the setup.
We set up a company,
we're doing all the required government
regulations, accounting.
all those things where they're now not
having to do that. So there's,
it's a more expensive offering,
but it comes with that.
The other alternative,
I got to set up an entity that's 10s of
thousands of dollars and ongoing
maintenance. There's a lot to it.
So sometimes when they're new to the EOR
type of arrangement,
it can be a little bit shocking, but
Once they understand it,
then it usually is like, okay,
that makes more sense. So yeah, okay.
So again,
this is what I'm looking at from a client
perspective. I guess quickly go in there,
make sure all the payroll looks good and
approve it from there.
Reimbursements happen through our system.
So employees would submit any
reimbursable expenses.
expenses, I can go and review all those.
And I can do it by engagement.
I can go into my EOR employees here,
and then that will pull up just them.
Let's look through all of them.
There we go. All the expenses, right?
And I can look into those quickly,
see what the expense is.
The receipt gets popped up here,
just like any other expense system you're
using. Now we want to,
those EOR employees,
we want to do the reimbursable expenses
through us as we're the employer of
record.
We need to double check that they're
obviously legitimate and that in some
countries, they may or may not be taxable.
So we just always have to process that
through the system.
And as long as they're approved before
the cutoff date,
they'll be paid out in the next paycheck.
Time off as well.
I can view all my time off requests here.
Now in as an employer of record in Mexico,
particularly,
we will have all and honor all the
statutory holidays that are provided in
Mexico, along with any paid time off,
leaves, any of those types of things.
As the employee of record,
we must honor what the Mexican government
states as the baseline.
You can always offer more.
Talking to another client the other week
where they give all their international
employees US holidays off as an extra
bonus. But we can't,
unless you are paying in holiday pay,
you have to honor the vacations and
holidays that they have in Mexico,
which are going to be different.
in the United States,
sometimes a lot more than what we're used
to here.
Well, we manage that all for you.
You don't have to worry about what those
Okay.
are. We manage all the vacation,
all the paid time off,
all the accruals and so forth,
and I'll show you how that looks.
Yeah,
and there's other reminders and so forth.
So that's kind of what the dashboard
looks like. I can look at my overall team.
Again,
if I can look at the types of workers
that they are.
Here's the type in my EOR workers here.
I can look and see where they're at.
Some are pending signature.
They've been onboarded,
but still hasn't completed that process.
And then here I can look at all my active
employees here from an EOR perspective.
And I can look at them specifically,
look at their contract,
what they're making.
Let's look at their profile directly.
And I can see all the documentation that
might be listed there,
any payments that I have made to her
throughout the months,
what her contract looks like, time off,
reimbursement, all that is located here.
So this is kind of your HR system that
you're seeing,
that your client is seeing for their team.
Let's see, I want to get over to here.
There we go. So here's,
I'm just let me look at Anna real quick
and show you a little bit more
information as an EOR employee. Again,
the time off is important.
It's going to have all the public
holidays.
So here's the Netherlands is going to
show all the public holidays that she has
allowed.
what type of sick leave, annual leave.
There's lots of different categories in
different countries,
but we track all of that here.
And so when I want to create a request,
I just go into here, you know,
what is this going to be for?
When is this happening?
Is it an annual leave, sick leave,
et cetera, partial full day,
and then that gets sent off for approval.
The nice thing is that you can...
set up who is going to approve that work
off. I can set up as a direct manager.
I can have different levels of approval,
but all that happens here in the system.
So then Anna can then see exactly how
many days up.
There's my reminder that my employee has
just submitted a time off request when I
go in there and approve that.
Some.
So that's kind of the some of the things
that you can look at from an employee
standpoint.
If, if we do,
if we happen to do payroll only for a
client,
is all of the holiday stuff tracked as
well? Like, is it still?
Do you still make sure they're compliant?
I mean,
all that's the same interface and
everything.
Yeah.
It is all the same interface.
It has all that same information. Yeah,
OKOK, got it.
that's the nice thing about this platform
is regardless of the classification,
we're going to load into the system all
of that. So if they are taking time off,
Okay.
they can go into our system. Now,
if they have their own tracking system
that they want to use in that country,
that's perfectly fine because their
company, their entity in that country,
They just need to report that here to us
through payroll, that hey,
so and so took time off,
please apply accordingly.
Or they can use our system as well.
So kind of depending on what they want to
do, if they've already set up an entity.
I have a question. This is Helen.
So what I'm hearing is that you say we,
we, this.
Through this global program,
Prism is actually handling this
themselves.
This is not something that surely our new
client manager would do as far as set it
up. If I came with a client,
I'd give the information to you.
You would set it up.
You would set the holidays up.
If there was any HR handbooks,
this is something that you would all do.
in the language of the country that I'm
in.
Or is this something that we just work,
you give us the platform and we do the
work?
Yeah, it's all loaded into the platform,
so all the...
OK, and we we handle it.
Correct, yeah. So from it,
and it really depends on, again,
Okay, bye.
the classification. If you're,
if it's an employer of record,
then they are our employees.
So we manage all that.
Most of what you would consider in a
handbook is actually outlined in an
employment contract.
So a lot of that is signed between the
Pitt.
employee and us as the employer of record.
You being you being you being you, right?
Not XLHR, you being FRISM.
So, a lot of that.
Prism.
So this is so if it's an EOR,
then you handle everything, not my office.
Correct. Yes.
It's all handled by,
so it's a whole different a whole
Correct.
different service team that I'm dealing
with,
as opposed to my internal service team.
Okay, understood. Okay.
Yeah, yeah. So,
and that's a great question.
Once the employee is identified and we
start the onboarding process,
then our Prism HR global team,
they're the ones that are managing the
onboarding, the implementation,
answering any questions from either your,
The communications, right? Got it.
absolutely. Yeah.
And the way that works is you are
assigned a global account manager.
that person resides in the United States.
So it's not too bad with time zone.
I'm in Arizona, I know East Coast,
that's three hours,
but they're in the United States.
So you can ask questions on anything that
Right.
Okay.
comes up.
We also have HR managers in region or
Okay.
sometimes in country for the employee or
yourself.
So if there's a more detailed HR question
that your account manager doesn't know,
They'll reach out to the HR manager in
that region or country,
get the specific information, et cetera.
So you have people you can reach out to.
Understood.
In this world of AI, which is great,
there's lots of information out there,
Under 6.
but it's always nice to have someone that
lives in country or region to talk to.
Sometimes when you get into different
leaves is really critical.
The maternity leave is coming up.
How does that work in Mexico?
Talking through that,
you'll have someone you can talk with, so.
Right.
..
Yeah,
and I guess one thing to note is if it's
our client,
like we're probably communicating with
our client, but with the EOR,
you communicate with the employee to get
them on board and the contract signed and
all that stuff. Like, yeah,
that's how it's been in the past, Helen,
same way.
Yep, correct.
Yeah, yeah.
But we're still the interface for our
client, right? It's just.
Right, exactly. Yes. Okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And can we work on the best way to
Yeah.
communicate that, you know,
that information,
whether the client or the employee is
going directly to us or going through you,
we can work through the mechanics of that.
We just want to make sure that you or
they have a direct contact.
You have people that you're going to,
that are supporting this employee and
your client in those countries.
Now, something to be mindful of,
if they have an entity that they've
established in another country and
they're paying these people directly,
then all we are doing is processing
payroll.
The HR is being done by your client in
that country directly.
Employment contracts, handbooks,
any other policies and so forth.
that HR aspect would be handled by them
in that country.
We can provide some ancillary HR
consulting support,
but because we are not the employer of
record in that scenario,
their legal entity is the employer of
record, they have that responsibility.
Well, does that make sense?
I hope that I was able to.
It does. Yeah, no,
you answered my questions. Thank you.
Okay.
Yeah.
Good. Okay.
Let me show you how that onboarding looks
like, if that's okay.
And it's really pretty simple.
The platform goes through all of this.
So a new employee is identified,
we want to hire this person. The client,
or if you're helping a client on your
side,
you could also do this on their behalf,
would then need to start and initiate
that onboarding process.
And the first question they ask,
is it a contractor or an employee?
and the selection would be employee and
then is it an employer of record or
through their entity.
Let's take the scenario in Mexico where
it was an employer of record.
First,
I would just fill in the information here,
right?
On.
And then the address,
let me just put my address in there.
There we go.
This is key information that seems
intuitive, but it's worth noting.
What is the employee's nationality? Now,
we'll say Mexico. There we go.
And where is the employee working from?
Okay, they're also working in Mexico. Now,
you may run across clients that are like,
oh, he's a Canadian.
working in Mexico.
Those scenarios pop up once in a while.
That would require visa, immigration,
or work permits.
So those two questions are important that
you always need to ask.
What country are they working in and are
they a citizen of that country?
They may go, oh no,
they're not from Mexico,
they're from Guatemala. Okay, well,
Do they have a work permit?
So there's other questions. Now,
if I put in here their nationality was
from Malawi, then it would say,
is this employee authorized to work in
Mexico, yes or no?
And then that gets us the information
that we need to get our immigration team
involved if there's any work permit visas
that need to come up. Most of the time,
The person's a nationality is the place
they're working in.
But just be mindful that we can support
visas and work permits in most countries,
but that's a different process.
So let's just go here. Okay.
We have now published on our website,
so you can go to that actually at any
moment. Antaeus maybe can drop the link.
But we have Global Glides out or out now.
So you can go into Sea in Mexico,
get all the details of holidays and
vacations and leaves and all the things
that go into that available to anyone.
We'll go next, job title,
let's just make something up.
They're project manager, maybe mid-level,
they're a PM.
This would be where you'd fill in some of
that information on their job description.
Beforehand,
I can set up different divisions for my
client,
whether they're engineering or product or
whatever division you'd like to put them
in.
So maybe they're in the engineering
division.
back-end development and they're on the
operations team.
However you like to classify that or your
client, you can set that up accordingly.
Location-wise,
I can put in specific cities,
office locations, remote,
whatever I'd like to do.
Maybe they're just in the field.
I can now assign a manager to them.
So let's go into here and let's assign
John Manager as a manager,
and that's all set up here.
Start date, if this was being done today,
you can see that the 26th is the earliest
I could start.
We usually need about a two-week window
to do all the required onboarding and
other requirements to start that person.
So starting someone the next day
internationally is not common at all,
but usually a two-week window is
sufficient in all countries to get that
person onboarded and started.
So, I'll select that.
Okay. Information on their pay,
the gross salary would be in pesos,
something to consider.
All our employer of record services,
we pay the individuals in their local
currency. Okay.
The invoice we send between us is in US
dollars,
but we always pay the employees and of
course the taxes in local currency.
And I forget exactly what the ratio is
there, et cetera. OK.
Full-time employment, indefinite.
If I wanted to add a different allowances,
say I want to add a mobile allowance,
right, at a monthly rate.
1000 pesos, I can add that payment here.
Okay. Vacation, again,
they're all getting the statutory
vacation days,
but if they want to have any that are
additional to that, you can add that here.
So as I do next,
this is a good indication on did I put in
the right amount?
I put in 10 million pesos is $500,
000 a month. That's not quite right.
So let me go back
and adjust that. Put too many zeros.
Let's go next.
10,000 pesos of 500.
We'll use that for those purposes.
But I really like that feature because if
you a little fat thumb and put an extra 0
and suddenly they're getting 5,000 or 50,
000,
it gives you an idea of what the currency
conversion is,
especially in those currencies where it's
a big number, right? Indian,
Real or in the millions,
but what does that mean in US dollars?
So it's a nice little calculation.
So let me confirm that.
Equipment,
the next question that comes up is how is
that person going to get their laptop,
cell phone, any of those types of things.
And we have a partnership.
It's actually a new partnership that
we're going to be uploading here soon
called TextPal.
They can get equipment to anyone in the
world in about 3 days.
So through that partnership, you can say,
yes,
I'd like to have this equipment sent to.
my worker there.
One thing we've noticed and that is very
common,
sending laptops or computer equipment
internationally is very lengthy and
sometimes gets caught in customs for
quite a while.
So this partnership that we have,
you can use,
or if you want to just reimburse them,
they purchase the equipment outright,
they can do that as well.
So your client has those
Options available.
And then last would be any premium
benefits.
So let me explain that how that works.
In Mexico,
they're going to have statutory benefits
that come automatic through your payroll
taxes that they're going to be paying.
And a lot of European countries,
South American countries,
they have a lot of socialized health care.
So that it comes included.
There's nothing you can do about it.
It's automatic. If you would like to
or your client would like to offer
additional benefits over and above that,
these are what these plans are about.
Many times I look at it as the government
sponsored programs is public health care.
This is private health care.
So in some countries, it's very common.
Other countries, it's not as common.
Your client can elect to pay for this
over and above their salary.
And as you can see,
they're pretty reasonable.
This is a per person rate.
So if they have dependents,
it would be 130 or 210 per month per
person that they'd be covering.
And the client would need either to cover
all of this or elect not to. Okay,
so that's an option that they have as
well.
And if they choose that,
then we have national partners and I can
even look at the plans are right here so
they could see exactly what those health
plans look like, the coverages, et cetera.
Okay.
But these are global plans that we have
in place to supplement what might be
offered automatically.
Okay,
so we'll just select this one and move on.
And then here's just all the information.
Again,
a snapshot to make sure everything got
everything correct.
And once I submit that,
it tells you exactly what's going to
happen next. So with employer of record,
like I mentioned earlier,
there's an employment contract that's
generated, and that's between Prism HR
and the employee directly.
Before we get to that point,
we send an offer letter to the employee.
And that just contains their salary,
any additional benefits,
everything that they would need to know
in that employment contract.
And we work through that offer letter.
Once everything's approved,
then we set out the employment contract
for signature.
Only when that employment contract is
signed,
with the start date in that contract is
when the official employment begins.
But we manage that entire process.
The employee is also going to get an
e-mail and allows them to enter into
their own platform and fill out all their
personal information,
their banking information, et cetera,
so that we can get them paid
appropriately.
So if I go to onboarding.
And I can see my employer record.
There's John Smith in Mexico is a waiting
offer letter.
That's when your global account manager
will get that information,
get everything confirmed, let you see,
or let your, I always say you,
but I'm talking about your client,
would be able to see that offer letter
before we initiate the employment
contract.
So,
I know I went through that kind of
What is,
let me let me ask a question about the
quickly, but...
employment contract.
Yeah, yeah.
Who's the actual employer?
Is it Prism HR or?
Yes, in most countries it is.
In some countries we do have a partner.
So I'd say throughout Africa,
maybe some Southeast Asia countries,
we don't have our own direct entity.
We would have a partner that would be
providing that actual employment boots on
the ground. All the services,
everything flows through this platform,
that nothing changes.
But most of the time,
we are the employer directly in that
country.
Okay.
So, we're just back, Bill,
we're just a reseller, actually.
Yeah, no, that's fine. I mean,
it's fine because we're,
There, there the, yeah, yeah, yeah.
we know what we're paying and what we're
charging, right? But I'm just wondering,
Right, exactly, yeah.
Right, yeah.
like...
You know,
if this is like an extension of our
domestic business, like...
It's not because it's not XLHR.
I guess it's, well,
there's no conflict of interest is what
I'm trying to get to, right? Like,
no one's going to talk to our domestic
clients. But they don't now, so it's fine.
It's fine. But is it, I was wondering,
No.
Yeah, yeah.
is it venture or is it Prism HR?
It's.
The legal entity,
I'm not sure what the name is per se.
Because we also, yeah,
I'm not sure exactly each country how
it's listed, if it's Prism HR,
if there's a company we acquired called
Yeah.
Listo,
it's all the back office support of all
this. It might be under their name,
but it's all under the venture corporate
Yeah, OK. Yeah, I guess it would be OK.
That's fine.
umbrella under Prism. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And we're adding more and more countries
every year to this.
It helps us have a closer pulse on the
direct market, on the HR rules,
everything going on there.
It just provides a much cleaner type of
system.
There will always be countries where we
use a partner for business purposes,
or like I said, there's not a lot of
Yeah.
U.S. interest in that country,
so we're gonna use a partner in that
country, so...
So that's going to be your team there.
Again, invoices are very cut and dry.
I showed you that. Time off, again,
I can go in there and approve all those.
Reimbursements. Reports.
Let me show you quickly some of the
reporting functionality here in the time
we have left.
EOR report here is I can see the employer
gross report.
So if I back up that a little bit.
I can see in each country,
I can see the wages and all the taxes and
to see my total burden, right?
So my wages are one thing.
We all know that taxes, you know,
on that total burden rate,
I can see what that is on a per country
basis. So that report's available.
I can also see what the gross to net
report is for all my employees.
So if I go back,
I can see here's my gross wages.
Here's all the taxes and so forth
calculated.
I have a general ledger report.
So if they want to import this into their
general ledger, they can do that here.
At the current time,
this would be an export import function.
but we're working on more APIs and so
forth, so that can be more automatic.
But as of right now,
exporting this into a format that can be
imported in the general ledger system.
And then the variance report as well,
this kind of shows the variances between
different pay periods.
One other tool that I like, and again,
all these tools,
these reports are per employee
classification.
So I'm going to see a similar thing in
the payroll side. Okay.
Right here in the tools and resources,
this is one of the coolest things that
you quickly can see in Mexico.
If I want to know what that employer
burden and the gross to net is,
I can quickly go into here, right?
Let's do 50,000, calculate that,
and it's going to tell me precisely what
the employer pays
what all the contributions are.
This is that detail we talked about
earlier for Mexico specifically. You see,
there's a lot of taxes in Mexico.
What the employee gets,
their gross to net here. Okay.
So you're going to see what, yeah,
go ahead.
I have a question. This is Helen.
So does PRISM provide all the necessary
insurances that a state or a country may
require?
So these are all provided by PRISM?
Okay,
and second question is that since we're a
reseller,
do we have any administrative access to
our client that we gave you or put there?
Do we have any access to those files?
You do.
If we want to, okay, alright.
Yeah, and I'll quickly show you.
I left it open.
Okay, alright.
Here is your administrative view as a
service provider.
Okay. Okay.
Here's a list of all your clients.
I could then in person,
Okay.
let's go to Cervelo Corporation.
I can impersonate them.
Now I'm diving into their system.
So now I, you can see all the information,
If you want to look at it, okay, good.
help them with reporting, et cetera.
Okay.
But that's how you would have access to
that. Yep. OK. Yep.
OK, alright, thanks.
I want to say this tool is very valuable.
In previous companies,
it would take me days,
sometimes weeks to get this information.
The fact that I can see it at my
fingertips is very valuable.
The nice thing about this, again,
if I go back to Mexico and I can see that
salary in US dollars.
So I feel like I want to pay that person
$5,000 a month.
I can calculate that all in US dollars.
So I can really see what those taxes are
in USD,
knowing that they'll be paid in Mexican
peso, but then I can say, okay,
that makes more sense to me in US dollars.
My $5,000 employee,
I'm going to roughly pay almost 6,
300 with the taxes included.
So I can show that in both currencies.
Annually,
this is going to account for any caps
that might happen with taxes, right?
Certain caps and then no longer available.
So if I toggle back and forth,
that's calculating those accordingly.
But to be able to see that in US dollars
or local currency is a very powerful tool
that your client would have access to,
you have access to,
that they can immediately see that impact
that that's going to have.
Some of our clients that are debating,
especially in Europe, France, Italy,
I'm not sure exactly where I want that
person to be.
By running these calculations,
you can see that there's a very different
tax burden based on the country.
So sometimes that's a helpful tool in
that respect.
I want to be mindful of time, Antaeus,
how we doing.
Any questions that you guys have,
anything else that you want me to show?
Hopefully this gives you an idea of how
the platforms work.
It's all very intuitive.
I like to say we have a tech-enabled
platform,
but we have a human component that you
always can have someone to talk to to go
through all this.
Yeah, I think we're right at time.
How about we open the floor to see if,
see Bill,
what are your thoughts overall so far?
Yeah, this was helpful.
I think it's like pretty intuitive.
And I know Shane,
I had asked you like at Prism Live,
how is this gonna like be more integrated
with the regular normal,
the domestic Prism HR over time? I don't,
I'm sure nothing's changed since we've.
We talked only a couple,
a month ago or whatever,
but a couple months. But like,
I'd be interested in that and just really
like to want to know if you have like a
rate card or something that shows kind of
those fees by like EOR versus payroll or
both like by country, that sort of thing.
or if there's a matrix or something,
or how we would get this quoted each time
around.
Yeah, yeah,
Antaeus can provide that to you.
I just want to quickly show, here's Prism,
Prism HR. Right now, it's single sign-on.
So if I go to payroll and then go to
global payroll,
that will take me into your system.
That's where we're at now.
I know we talked at Prism Live.
The report center functionality is what's
really top of mind and really priority
right now.
So at the moment,
the reports I showed you,
you have to go into the Prism global
system to get those reports. Future State,
which is coming up,
will there in Report Center be able to
pull all that global data in as well and
then use that along with your US employee
data. So that's coming.
And then just more of that integration
with Prism is happening.
I don't know at one,
I don't know at a future point if
everything will be in one platform.
That gets into some GDPR compliance and
Yeah.
some international standards that it
might still be a separate module,
but a lot more reporting integration,
right? So we're working all through that.
But I know the reporting is a big deal
and to be able to have one place to go to
to get all your
US and international reporting is
something that they're really working on
hard.
Okay.
Bill, as far as pricing,
what would you say is like the immediate
need right now for any given client that
you have?
Mexico.
Yeah, Mexico, maybe Canada.
Next account.
And then, I don't know,
if we could throw a couple other
countries out just because we've had some
experience looking into this,
just to get a general idea.
Um, we like Helen and I was saying,
there's probably a few clients that we
could go back to and say, "Hey,
we have potential now."
Absolutely, I agree.
Yeah.
So, I, you know, I think like,
I know Spain, I don't know,
there'd probably be a few other countries
I could think of.
One thing that my clients,
that I'm doing with them,
the other service providers I work with,
is that they're bringing me on to calls
with their clients.
So we can talk through this,
get really specific,
especially when you talk about different
countries. Once you get into Europe,
there's a lot of different things that
kind of blows people's minds.
South America,
once you start talking about 13th and
14th month payrolls,
People are like,
what are you talking about?
So there's some of those things that
we're always open to having those joint
calls. Antaeus can jump on those.
He's been in the business for a long time
to answer some of those specifics.
So they're not caught off guard.
Or sometimes they hear this from their
Brazilian employees,
like there's a 14th month payroll.
What are you talking about? We're like,
no, there really is.
And here's how it works. So
We're always available to help support
you in those sales processes.
Yo, Laura, what was the one we just had?
Somewhere in Africa? I forget the country.
Oh.
Yeah, it was Africa.
The employees moving to Africa from the U.
S.
So.
Right.
So it's a U.S. citizen going there.
They were working in the embassy, right?
The U.S. Embassy.
Her, I think her husband is a diplomat,
and that meant something to her.
Yeah.
They were trying to say they wouldn't be
subject to any taxes in this,
whichever country it was, but like,
it was Kenya, right? Okay. So like, yeah,
It was Kenya.
Yeah.
Interesting.
we looked into it and we determined that
they would be subject to their Kenyan
taxes. And so that's an example,
like where, you know, we would say,
Okay.
Yeah.
a US citizen working here.
And everything, but...
You know, they had a...
Yeah, those situations, yeah, are tricky.
What they're saying may be true,
but it depends on what they're doing for
work in that country in Kenya.
If they're working in the embassy,
Mhm.
probably. But if they're not,
they're working for a Kenyan company,
they're going to pay Kenyan taxes and
they're going to need a work permit and a
visa.
So there's all these little things that
come into play that we can absolutely
help with.
We have an immigration team that would
say, okay,
Yeah.
What's the scenario?
Here's how we can help.
Most countries we can help.
There are some countries that don't allow
EORs to sponsor work permits and visas.
Canada is a good example.
As an employer of record,
we cannot sponsor an individual,
a foreign individual to work in there.
They have to be hired directly from the
client. So there's, again,
different rules for different countries,
but we can...
Spell everything out so everyone's on
board with what's going on.
What is your minimum?
What's your minimum employee acceptance?
Okay.
If we come to you, one, okay. All right,
good.
One, yeah, just one.
I already asked that one.
Yeah, no, no minimums, yeah.
Okay, good. Okay.
Yeah.
It often starts with one,
but it goes from there, yeah.
Yeah, I think, I think that Canada...
Yeah, the Canada example,
I believe they are Canadians in that case,
OK.
so that's good.
But there have definitely been a lot of
Yeah, yeah.
like US citizens, retired military,
that sort of thing, working on like naval,
you know,
bases and all kinds of stuff there with
different contracts and stuff.
So that's where the immigration teams
Yeah, you should.
will come in and.
And everything.
Yeah, and in my experience,
usually when they're US going and working
on military bases,
they're covered under SOFA or other
agreements with that country,
and they actually don't,
Yeah, yeah.
we don't even get involved.
They stay on the US payroll. So again,
it depends on the situation.
It can get a little complicated,
but in some of those situations,
because they're technically working on US
soil in a foreign country.
They don't have to, but the spouses,
that's a scenario happens A lot, right?
I'm moving because of my spouse.
They're working through that company,
Yeah.
but now what do I do?
Now that their spouse gets a work permit,
they work for their company in the UK,
but my spouse can't work.
we can look at hiring through employer of
record and sponsoring the spouse to work.
So there's lots of ways we can help do
that.
Yeah, okay,
we've had every scenario there.
I think so, yeah.
And I mean, the whole thing is,
we had the people working on bases,
Yeah.
Yeah, and you'll see more, right?
Yep.
but like Germany,
they had to pay social tax and all that
stuff in Germany. So, you know,
the same client had people in all these
Yeah.
different places and they were all
different rules in each country. So.
Yeah.
Yeah, we kind of pieced it together.
So, Bill,
you guys have a smorgasbord of
opportunity, it sounds like.
Different clients, different needs,
different countries,
which is all fantastic now that we have
our global offering. But I'm curious,
like, what do you,
I want to hear from you,
what do you think would be helpful for
you as a next best step?
I think it would be knowing what we would
be charged so that we could build a
proposal as we would either go back to
these guys or as the new opportunities
really come to fruition here.
There's one that we just need to get in
touch with our client to see what the
Mexico opportunity actually is.
So that's the most immediate.
You would say that that's probably the
most immediate, yeah, okay, yeah.
Yeah, but you know, like they,
that same client had people in Canada and
we actually referred that somewhere else.
So we could look at potentially bringing
Yeah.
Bring that, yeah,
we can probably bring that back.
that back in the fold.
Do you know if they,
so you don't think they've engaged a
third party yet, the Canadian opportunity?
Yes, they have, they have, yes, yes.
I think they have, yeah,
but they would probably be open to,
We could prop, yeah, we could,
we could circle back on it, yeah.
you know, looking at...
Yeah.
And how many employees,
you may or may not know this,
the Mexican opportunity,
the Mexico opportunity and the Canadian
opportunity.
Do you know how many employees they were
looking to hire in each country?
Well, Canada, there's 10 already hired.
They're already working.
Yeah.
Yeah, so I know that.
What's the what's this?
And.
You said already hired, so is there...
Yes,
they they've already they've been they've
How many are they?
already proposed 2 months of payroll in
Canada,
so that's that job is completely
onboarded.
Okay.
Oh,
so 10 is the number or are they do they
But...
Yeah, and...
have more headcount space that they're
looking to fill in in Canada?
Yes.
But we don't know that number.
No, we don't know the number,
but you know we we can possibly go back
Okay, understood.
So...
and get their business back, yeah.
One thing we don't know either, Helen,
or maybe you do,
Sure.
but did they do like an EOR in Canada
with that partner we referred them to,
or did they do payroll and do they have
an entity there?
Payroll.
They they did payroll.
Yeah,
so they probably have an entity
Ohh, OK, so they have an entity there, OK.
established already,
which would make it easier to switch,
I would assume.
Yeah, and then...
We would just manage it all through the
platform, right, that payroll instance.
Yeah.
No.
Some key things as you're talking to your
clients and they're like, oh,
we have an entity we set up in Canada.
Always ask the next question is,
is it registered for payroll?
There's those two components that
M.
sometimes get missed. Oh yeah,
our attorney set up the entity. Great,
we're ready to go.
Not quite.
You need to register that entity for
payroll.
I always tell the example when I was
hired at another company,
I was the first employee in Arizona.
And as you guys know,
if you've never done business in the
state,
you've got to register in that state for
payroll taxes. Same thing with countries.
So that's always a good little like,
are you registered yet? And if not,
then we can talk through what
Yeah.
registrations are required.
And then once that's complete,
we can run their payroll in that country,
no problem.
Okay.
Yeah, Bill and Jer.
And you're able to say now,
Bill and Helen, yeah, we can do all that.
We're already, I mean, if we just,
you know, break it down to brass tacks,
We do.
that's literally what we raised this
product for. So go ahead, Helen,
I'm sorry.
No, in Germany, yes,
each employee had to register with the
country.
Each individual employee had to register.
I remember that. It was a disaster.
Yeah, Mexico has a, yeah, yeah,
Mexico has a specific registration
Well, it's yeah.
A disaster.
process. Some countries, Europe,
Philippines, France,
they have medical checks you have to go
to. Yeah,
so it depends on what's going on.
There's a lot, lots that goes on, so.
Okay.
So let me ask you this with payroll only
in Canada,
So...
like if these guys were registered for
payroll, everything, and they switched,
is it like the US where you would have to
bring in like, I mean,
do they have like the equivalent of a W-2
so you would need to have the annual
wages?
All the history in there as well.
OKOK.
Yep, similar process.
I don't know what the W-2 is called in
Canada, but yeah,
all those tax information we would have.
Yeah.
Our teams would then migrate that system
over to us.
We usually do a parallel run or test the
system the last,
T2 or something.
they would do the last run on their side.
We'd test it on our side and then cut
over on the cutoff date and we'd take
over payroll from there.
And then we manage all the tax forms and
submissions from there. So
Yeah, Bill, Bill,
you just need to get us rates as to what
Yeah, okay.
the cost would be in Canada,
because we would do a January 1.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's another thing option there,
yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah, just we just need rates, yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, in that respect,
we're processing the payroll.
We even create the bank file,
which tells their bank in Canada which
employees to pay what and to pay the tax
authorities. So in that respect,
they're not paying through us like an
employer of record model does. Instead,
we're processing the payroll and then
directing their Canadian bank
Who to pay and when to pay?
With an employer of record, you,
the client, I keep saying you,
I mean the client,
pay us all the salaries, taxes,
and fees they pay to us,
because we're the employer than we pay in
local currency. Yeah.
Right, right.
Yeah, that, that's like, that's like us,
yeah.
Yeah, OK.
So I'll wrap all this up for us, Bill,
Helen, and team.
I just heard right there at the end,
Helen said it would be good to see what
our payroll offering pricing would be for
Canada. Is that what I heard?
Yeah, right. Yes,
and I'd like Mexico also, so I can,
Yep. Yes,
I'll break out payroll EOR for those two
you know, please.
to start,
because like you've been hearing us say,
it just, I mean, right,
every country is a different bottle of
wax.
And I'll also send over,
just so you guys have it for your other
clients,
just like the top few questions that
you'll want to know that'll help us be
able to provide you with pricing.
For any given country that your clients
come back to you and say, "Hey,
we need we need we need support in these
countries,
" but we'll start with Canada and Mexico.
Yeah, anything else?
Thank you guys for staying over a little
Yeah.
bit. Any other questions?
I don't think I have any.
Yeah.
Okay,
well so good to meet with all of you.
Let us know what we need to help.
It was good to meet you and go through
Yeah.
this with you.
Thank you so much. Appreciate your time.
All right. Bye.
Thank you.
Alright, yep. Thanks a lot, guys.
Appreciate it.
Thank you.
Thanks, everybody. Yep. Talk soon. Bye.